Welcome everyone
My name is Konstantin and I like to code
Video that you will see today is kind of an experiment
I'm gonna do some live coding
There was one podcast
I was listenting to recently
It's called "Odin Doma"
or, in English, "Home Alone"
This podcast is in Russian language, so
I'm not sure how this is relevant to you,
but what what caught my eye recently
when I was listening to this podcast
is that it has really good intro and outro music
Which I'd like to collect somehow and
listen to this music alone
So, here is the task...
I'm gonna toggle floating notes
The task is to...
get intro and outro audio from podcast
And here is the URL of the particular episode,
what we want is the podcast itself
So, and, I mean, ideally, I want to save all
these tracks to Spotify playlist
So every podcast, as you may know,
is an RSS feed
Which looks like this
Let's look at this in the console
I did some preparation a few minutes before
just to look into this
This is an XML file with
some description of the podcast and episodes
There is
item for each episode with description,
which is HTML,
and with iTunes summary in plain text,
and also "content:encoded", also
HTML, but escaped HTML characters
The easiest thing would be is to parse them from
iTunes summary because it's a plain text
And I could do just some regexp extraction
of these tracks
And I'm gonna use Chrome for that, let's see...
Oh, sorry, not Chrome,
I'm gonna use Go to do all of that stuff
First of all, let's create a new repo
repo.new
And I will be an owner, the repo name
"odindoma-music"
I'll keep it private for now, License...
MIT, why not?
Git ignore...
maybe you have something for Go?
Yeah, some default Go .gitignore
Create the repo, and now it's empty
Ok, let's clone it
I use my own alias to put
projects where I want them to be
regardless from where I run this command from
And I open...
I use VSCode to do all of the development
Let's zoom in a bit
With every project I start with
main.go file, of course
Typing all of things myself,
well, with some Copilot help
go mod init, OdinDoma music
go mod tidy
Created go.mod file, no dependencies
of course not
"Should have a package comment",
alright, let's make one
A small app to parse RSS feed for
Odin Doma podcast
and save tracks...
Well, let's start with "print"...
"print out"...
"the tracks"
And we will need to
get the actual feed from there, so...
Feed URL is...
this one
Still need to log "Starting..."
And I prefer to do this thing with "run"
just to
track errors
Run...
Alright, let's try to run this small program
Good
Now, we need to actually grab content
from this URL
To do that we will use the standard HTTP client,
we will get bytes from this feed URL
If it fails return the error,
or rather, wrap the error with some meaningful message
Don't forget to close the body and...
I need to read the whole bytes array, so...
unless we can use decoder with...
decoder that reads Reader right away.
Let's make sure that bytes are there first, so...
Printf...
This will actually be response
Here we go, all of the body
Now we need to parse this XML
To decode it first,
let's make some...
Podcast inter...
eh, struct
where I will need to...
we will parse it into
I may not need it all, but...
I'm gonna parse just a few first things
So, XML, channel,
XMLName, channel
Probably, Title, yeah?
I don't know, let's...
And variable where we will read this into
And unmarshal these bytes into the structure
Will this work?
Oops, alright
We parsed the XML
Originally I was thinging about including some
library to parse XML,
to not write strucure myself, but now
it's kinda pretty simple,
so I don't want to do this anymore
Let's just write it ourself for this thing
We need all the items
All we really need from the item is iTunes summary
Don't need this anymore, don't need this...
Will make this unexproted
Let's iterate over the items,
printing just the summary
Something didn't work well
What is it?
Item, channel,
item
itunes:summary
from the item
Let's see if any other fields are decoded,
like Title
Oh, in the Item I meant
Title on the item...
Nope, I suspect the whole item array is empty
Yeah, something wrong with this struct
Channel and item, ...
So...
What is wrong with this?
Oh, oh, I think missed this one
Yey!
What?
Alright
We got all the items, now
let's check the body
Not really
Is it?
"itunes:summary"
yeah
What about description?
It is there, but not summary?
Do I need to escape it somehow, maybe?
I don't know, just trying something
Well, well... alright let's see
XML
decoder go
colon
"How to unmarshal parameter with colon"
Yes, how to do this?
Space?
Space? Alright
Still empty
"Unmarshal", "abc:name"
Namespace
"XMLName field has an associated tag of the
form "name" or "namepsace-URL name...""
"must have the given name (and, optionally, name space)"
Maybe,
I don't know
Yay,
alright, we got all the summaries
Here they are,
Next step is to
parse
intro and outro audios
Let's look at them...
Intro podcast and outro
Let's go to regex101.com to make/test such regexp
So, imagine our
text is like this
Well, no, I don't want line numbers in there
The thing is I want this to be multi-line,
there are multiple things per item
Let's test it only for first matching item
Don't need to replace
And not on the Title, but on summary
Let's just print the first summary
that matches that regexp
No... nice
"MatchString"...
Does Go support multiline regexp match?
Seems like it does
Will that work?
Yay
Alright
So we got the first
match
now we need to extract information from there
This is just the one?
And not both
Which means we need something like
FindStringSubmatchAll, you know?
FindStringAll, All!
I just need all
FindAllSubmatch... maybe?
FindAllSubmatch...
maybe?
FindAllStringSubmatch
Ok, Intro this track,
Outro this track
Looks good, now let's see it for all of these,
All of the episodes
Yay
That is working, but
It's kind of a small list as well
Just 55, well, 50 or so
Well, I mean, maybe it's fine
Ok, this would be good enough already,
Maybe it's fine
Ok
This would be good enough already,
Let's double check, maybe
I missed some formatting
Yeah, I need to be careful about this
escaped HTML
It was there at least? Yeah
Why this one isn't detected?
Oh, because it says
not the "podcast" but the "episode"
alright
Now, this will be 3
65, ok, a bit more
Ok, before he also
formatted it differently
This is a bit more challenging because
format isn't always the same
But we can try anyway
So, it's either that regexp
or different one
regIntroOutro
and this one is...
Something like, I don't know...
Episode
Let's ignore the first one for now
and print out only these
"previously formatted" episodes
Alright
There is, I would say some kind of pattern,
let's try
So,
I need something like
everything, but what stops at word
"song" or "composition"
Song, composition or track
or cover
Maybe "song of some group"
Oops, track meaning...
And, ideally, to extract
name of the song and...
the author,
something like...
Singer, group, ...
Maybe not,
maybe it's getting to complicated
Let's extract just
this unhighlighted text on them...
This one isn't matched
Looks good, but
Yeah, maybe not as easy to
parse the "sub", let's see
First, parse the regexp,
maybe even like this...
And we need just the last match
Alright, it is in the end of the list, right?
Yes
Episode
Need to trim this a bit,
or, rather,
add an optional space maybe
Where is that?
"Smalltown Boy"
Oh yeah, there is that space
Wow, all... not all of... yes...
I can't...
I'd need put it down here
yes I can...
I need to trim the dot there as well
Okay
let's print alltogether
Oop, ah
There is space in there...
exists there as well
Why is that?
What is this?
This isn't space?
What is this??
Non-breaking space. Wow
Ok
Is there a regexp for non-breaking space?
Wow, now it didn't match anything
Alraight, I can trim it afterwards then
Let's see, "strings.TrimLeft"
and this non-breaking space
Yep, ok
Now, ...
author, and then track name,
where here is track name and then author
Let's keep it like this for now, and...
will see, maybe we will use just
Spotify API and it will match
the audio right
Now, to print this all
Actually, let's
yeah, just print all regexs
And save them into
some file
Here we go, about 102 tracks.
Exactly 102 tracks.
The next step
is to actually use
Spotify API and then
somehow to read this
This becomes part one
New main file
Let's actually copy
most of the stuff
It's gonna read "tracks.txt" and print it
This app is supposed to find
tracks in Spotify
Tracks listed in the file...
via API
Ok, file is there
Now, let's see
Stripe API... oh, Spotify API
Spotify API
Never worked with that
Spotify for Developers, yay
"Login into Spotify account"
"Create an app"
"authorization", get "access token"
"Use the token in your API requests"
"You can follow Get started...", okay
"Tutorial", "you have a Spotify account" (I do)
"We will use cURL" – nice
So, let's get to the Dashboard
"A few moments later"
"Create an app"
Import tracks
App...
searches tracks in Spotify
by name and adds them to
specified playlist
Website? Sure
Redirect URI,
I'm pretty sure I'm gonna use localhost
for now
"spotify-callback"
"Save"
"Settings"
"Client ID"
and "Client Secret"
And don't worry,
before publising this video I will
rotate the secret,
so don't even bother
And that's it,
it, let's see what else
Get the token with the secret
Access token for 1 hour, I think
And then we can do some things like this
And there is Search API
Search for an item, yay
Query, Album,
Market
Ok, so first of all,
this is the Search API
And for playlist,
I want to get playlist, or maybe
list them?
Even maybe create one,
let's create one
"Create playlist" and
"Add item to the playlist"
"playlist_id", "position", "uris",
"uri", all that...
these tracks
Seems to be more or less clear
One thing anyway I also wanted to check is also
API rate limits
"rolling 30 second window", alright
How many? How many calls?
"Exceeds"
Well, it doesn't tell you, maybe
Maybe it's in the dashboard
Quota, ...
quota extension request
in the dashboard
Nah, alright, there is some API request limit
Afterall, I don't think that
we will esceed this then
Well, well, well, well
First of all, secrets
SPOTIFY_CLIENT_ID
is this one
SPOTIFY_CLIENT_SECRET...
this one
Now, I need to read this from environment variables
New dependency, the first one
go get,
go mod vendor
go mod tidy
Now we have this dependency
and this indirect dependency
Which is fine,
it's all downloaded here
which I will commit
Parsed the environment variables,
now to configure Stripe API client
Is there any...
egh, not Stripe
Is there any Spotify...
Go client?
There are should be
From some guy zmb3 wrapper
Can not read this GoDoc
Wrapper, ...
Auth
Redirect URL
Redirect handler, client
Authorization Guide
Ok, and what can you do then?
AddTracksToPlaylists – yes
Create playlist, maybe?
GetPlaylist
CreatePlaylistForUser
Alright
Search
Search query, with options as well
What are the options?
Limit number of items, ok
And in search result we will at Tracks
FullTrack with...
I need ID
And SimpleTrack has an ID, ok
I think...
Let's see also
Apache-2.0
Modification,
copyright notice...
will be in the vendor
This one is MIT
Stars... 1000
January 7th last release
Which actions do you have?
golangci-lint
Didn't update actions yet,
Which isn't that much time left I think, right?
When do they deprecating this?
Summer this year...
plan to migrate, ...
deprecation process,
effort... September 27th,
You don't have that much time
Have any PRs open?
ID, item...
Well, ok,
maybe will create an issue for this later
Meanwhile,
all I need is just the code
So go get...
oops, oh yeah
Protobuf?
AppEngine?
This looks like hallucination
New client
Why do you require AppEngine
and TWO versions of Protobuf?
Why?
Let's see,
right, now... some other dependencies you have
reference Protobuf then
Oh, you get it through this one?
Well, of course
Where are your dependencies?
oAuth2/internal and from there,
there is Protobuf
Because everyone needs Protobuf, ok
Token, internal,
and here is our AppEngine with urlfetch
Just out of curiosity,
is there any other "in Go" client?
Terminal UI
Yeah,
dosn't look like it, alright
Redirect URL
What's next?
SetAuth,
get URL for auth...
and handle redirect
Authenticator
It's not true
Goes in the Options...
In the New, alright
What is the state?
"Unique state identifying the session"
What's here is some random string
It's not random enough, come on
Oh, thant's fine
Let's print this URL
Alright,
read the environment variables
So this is the URL we need to click
Oh come on
"Invalid redirect URI"
Oops, yeah
"View your Spotify data"
I want more than just "view", so...
"WithScopes"...
Do we set sopes?
"Scopes – strings"
Let's see documentation what scopes
are there
"playlist-read-private"
"PlaylistModifyPrivate"
What else?
Search
This should be enought I think
"View your activity, take actions",
yes
And when I agree
it goes to localhost,
but nothing listens there
Let's fix that
I'm kinda need to run server,
but
stop it afterwards.
I need Context
Which one?
Let's create a background one
Ideally I want to save this token for the next start
And
this starting to look pretty massive, so
I want to extract it into a separate file
in a few minutes
So once I have the token
I can just encode this JSON
So this will save the token
Let's try
Well, I didn't start the server
"Could not get token"
Why?
"Invalid client secret"
Interesting
Oops, there is a typo, I think
Yeah
Now what?
Same error, oh, I didn't refresh the
environment variables
Okay, now there should be token there.
Yay
Let's see...
Ok
Token is there
Let's say the purpose of this particular
app is to grab the token,
so, this one is done
Once we get the token,
"os.Exit(0)"
And something like
"Token saved to file"
And this should be enough
Let's double check one more time that its working
I'm gonna remove the token
And run this again
"Refused to connect"?
Well, token is there, that's all what relevant
In theory I could tell to the user that
all is good
Something like
"print success message and exit"
"Login Comlpeted!"
Ok, let's try
Egh, whatever
I'd rather do that later
This token is saved,
so I'm gonna use this in the next app
So, the actual purpose of this app is to
grab
token from Spotify API and save it to file
New app
It's gonna be partly the same
This one
Use token file
to
Create Spotify client and
handle tracks
No need for redirect anymore
I would need some context background
And now I need to create client, finally
How to do this, again?
"auth.NewClient"
So, just "Client", alright
And I'll need to read the token from file
If it were that easy
Alright, Client should be created this way then
Actually, let's extract this into something like
"createClient"
All I need is
HTTP client
To talk to Spotify
Wait a second, where are all these
convenient methods
that I would use on the client itself
Like Playlist
"PlaylistTracks"
Get playlist from the client
Client is this one, not "http", oh
Do I need to manually create one?
What?
"Retry"...
Now we're talking
Let's get current user
I am logged in, yes!
Ok, this is the final stretch, I guess
We need to open the file with the tracks,
go over each track
Then,
search the track...
Let's start with that
I want to read file line by line
And yeah, this time we don't need to use any
configs or client,
just reading tracks line by line
Nice, now
I need to handle it
Handle it with the client
What does "handle" mean?
"Handle" mean search for this track
I only need tracks,
with, I don't know, limit of 10, maybe
Let's handle just the first line first
Wait, wait, wait, stop
I need to ad break, I though...
Yeah,
so in the tracks the first line
"Blawan – Under Belly"
And here is the track
That kinda works
How about
something like that?
That works too
Thing with it...
with a typo still works
(the first item)
What about this one?
Two tracks, but
I think the first one just
would do, let's see
Two tracks,
one from...
Okay, this is the first example of this not
really working,
And I think this is acceptable
Not every track we will be able to find
on Spotify
Although, this one is there.
How about
I remove this in between...
Ok, this one works
Works too
Okay, I'm gonna just gonna go with what I have,
I think it will work for most of the tracks
For those where it will not,
maybe I will add the wrong track
into the playlist
So, maybe some check will be required afterwards
But, first of all,
we need to create a new playlist
"CreatePlaylist" for my user
Public?
No description,
not public,
not collaborative yet
I may change this manually later in Spotify
And I only need to run this once,
so I will comment this out later
"FullPlaylist"...
Limit to one track.
The first one is the only one we care about
Return "err" if there is any error
Now, to my Spotify playlists
Yeah, I don't have this
"Odin Doma" playlist yet
So
This might be the time when it will create one
Wait, let me add some logging
"Creating playlist..."
"Reading tracks from file..."
"Searching for track..."
"Adding track to playlist..."
Alright
I might hit API rate limit error soon,
Will see how far it will go
And it's done,
Let's see,
(is there) any new playlists that I have? Ok
Looks like it created it twice
The first time I ran it without logging
And second time
when I let it run till the end
So I'm gonna delete this one,
I don't need this anyway
And here are we go,
this is the whole playlist with 102 tracks
I don't think...
Yeah, I have exactly 102 tracks, but
maybe,
maybe, not all of them are the correct ones
Let's check
I'm gonna go over this file...
Actually, let me create a backup
and in the original file I'm gonna go
and remove what I think is a good match
So this one is definitely fine...
I think I wouldn't spend this much time for the last
for the last few minutes
trying to find the tracks
if I were
more careful with regexp,
I think I'm trimming too much somewhere...
somewhere maybe in here,
some last character
Also, I could've
remove text in between,
apprarently, that improves search results
And I also could've check the returned
Spotify track title
against the line content,
because sometimes
they don't exactly match,
like if they different
"apart from each other" for about 50%,
then I could report this
and not add track to the playlist
And that's about it
Thank you for watching,
Let me know what you think about this...
experimental coding excercise,
Feel free share any ideas in the comments,
Don't forget to like...
and subscribe?
I'm not sure if I will do this one more time,
probably will
Thank you for watching, bye